A Guide to the Anne Douglas Sedgwick Letters, 1922-1929
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Anne Douglas Sedgwick Letters, 1922-1929
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
8459-b
This collection consists of 15 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased by the Library from Charles Apfelbaum, Rare Books and Collections, Valley Stream, New York, on September 17, 1986.
Scope and Content Information
In this series of letters Anne Douglas Sedgwick (Anne de Selincourt) writes to Henry Chester Tracy discussing his impending visit; several manuscripts he has given her to read; the illness of her father; stories and books she has read; his visit to Chartres; the writing of several of her books and those of her husband Basil de Selincourt; her declining health; and her life in the English countryside.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Anne Douglas Sedgwick, Far End, Kingham, Oxon, to Henry Chester Tracy, Long Island, New York 1922 Sep 19, 4 p. on 1 l., w/ env., ALS
  She writes after having read his letter and wishing to have him visit.
- Anne Douglas Sedgwick to Henry Chester Tracy, Oxford Tuesday, 1922 Oct 17, 4 p. on 1 l., w/ env., ALS
  Inviting him to lunch and tea on Friday and giving information on train schedules
- Anne Douglas Sedgwick to Henry Chester Tracy Wednesday, 1922 Oct 18, 4 p., on 1 l., w/ env., ALS
  Expressing her pleasure at his plans to visit
- Anne Douglas Sedgwick to Henry Chester Tracy Monday, 1922 Oct 23, 4 p. on 1 l., w/ env., ALS
  After having read "the last batch of mss you left --" and admiring his style, while indicating her inability at expressing things
- Anne Douglas Sedgwick to Henry Chester Tracy Saturday, 1922 Oct 28, 4 p. on 1 l., w/ env., ALS
  Expecting him on "Friday next, the 3rd," and writing how she expresses herself in her books "sheltered behind the personalities of my characters"
- Anne Douglas Sedgwick to Henry Chester Tracy, Loughton, Essex 1922 Nov 10, 1 p., APCS
  Saying she thought he was in France, and explaining her delay in writing about his manuscript
- Anne Douglas Sedgwick to Henry Chester Tracy 1922 Nov 11, 4 p. on 1 l., ALS
  Sending his letters and manuscripts, asking about his going to Chartres, and apologizing for "a rather rambling note"
- Anne Douglas Sedgwick to Henry Chester Tracy Wednesday, 1922 Nov 22, 4 p. on 1 l., w/ env., ALS
  Mentioning his apparent pleasure in Chartres, Marcel Proust's death, and a volume of Henry James
- Anne Douglas Sedgwick to Henry Chester Tracy, Hollywood, California 1923 July 25, 4 p. on 1 l., w/ env, ALS
  Concerning her "burdened time" with her father and his uncle, expressing her pleasure at the publication of his book and giving news of her husband's publication of collected essays
- Anne Douglas Sedgwick to Henry Chester Tracy 1924 Sep 12, 4 p. on 1 l., w/ env., ALS
  Thanking him for the copy of his book and expressing her delight in seeing it in print, and telling him of a visiting niece
- Anne Douglas Sedgwick to Henry Chester Tracy, Los Angeles, California 1925 Apr 8, 4 p. 1 l., w/ env, ALS
  Thanking him and his wife, for the charming things they said about her book
- Anne Douglas Sedgwick to Henry Chester Tracy 1925 Dec 6, 8 p. on 2 l., w/ env, ALS
  Telling him that she has written a novel of "sheer self-indulgence and dissipation!" and that she is having one of her short stories sent to him, and inquiring of several general literary topics
- Anne Douglas Sedgwick to Henry Chester Tracy 1927 June 9, 3 p. on 1 l., w/ env., ALS
  Expressing pride at having his book dedicated to her
- Anne Douglas Sedgwick to Henry Chester Tracy 1927 Nov 18, 3 p. on 1 l., w/ env., ALS
  re having an American publisher send him a reprint of "The Religion of the Spirit" and beginning a new novel
- Anne Douglas Sedgwick to Henry Chester Tracy 1929 Sep 19, 8 p. on 2 l., w/ env., ALS
  re a review by Mary Ross of her book, [ Dark Hester], and giving some thoughts on this novel